maryland.gov 2017-12-12

# Maryland.gov Privacy and Security Policy - Maryland.gov

​​

Thank you for visiting a website published and managed by the State of Maryland Department of Information Technology. This statement applies specifically to Maryland.gov and State agency websites that have been authorized to link to this central privacy statement.

## Copyright

If you believe that any material contained on the Maryland.gov website (the "Site") infringes your copyright or other intellectual property rights, you may notify NICUSA, LLC, Maryland Information Division of your copyright infringement claim in accordance with the following procedure. NICUSA, LLC, Maryland Information Division will process notices of alleged infringement which it receives, and may take action as authorized by the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) and/or other applicable intellectual property laws if it has the ability to do so. The DMCA requires that notifications of claimed copyright infringement should be sent to this Site's Designated Agent:

By mail:  
NICUSA, LLC, Maryland Information Division DMCA Agent  
c/o Stinson Leonard Street  
Stinson IP Administrator, 1201 Walnut, Suite 2900, Kansas City, MO 64106

By phone: 816-842-8600  
By fax: 816-691-3495  
By email: [DMCA@stinsonleonard.com](mailto:DMCA@stinsonleonard.com)

To be effective, the notification must be in writing and contain the following information (DMCA, 17 U.S.C. 512(c)(3)):

  * Physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed;
  * Identification of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed, or, if multiple copyrighted works at a single online site are covered by a single notification, a representative list of such works at that site;
  * Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or claimed to be the subject of infringing activity and that is sought to be removed or access to which is sought to be disabled, and information reasonably sufficient to permit the location of the material;
  * Information reasonably sufficient to permit the service provider to contact the complaining party, such as an address, telephone number, and, if available, an electronic mail address at which the complaining party may be contacted;
  * A statement that the complaining party has a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; and
  * A statement, made under penalty of perjury, that the information in the notification is accurate and that the complaining party is authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed.

E-mails sent to [DMCA@stinsonleonard.com](mailto:DMCA@stinsonleonard.com) for purposes other than communication about copyright claims may not be acknowledged or responded to.

## Information Collected and Stored Automatically

When you browse these websites, read pages, or download information, certain information about your visit is automatically gathered and stored. This information does not identify you personally, and includes the following:

  * The internet domain (example: aol.com) and the IP address (the number automatically assigned to your computer when surfing the Web) from which you access the site, 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access the site,
  * The date and time you access a site,
  * The page(s) you visit,
  * The address from which you linked to our website.

This information is used to make these websites more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to our site, and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record identifying information about individuals and their visits.

## E-Mail

If you send us e-mail, we use the information you send us to respond to your inquiry, just as we do with written correspondence. E-mail correspondence, like mailed correspondence, may become a public record. As a public record, your correspondence could be disclosed to other parties upon their request, in accordance with Maryland's public records law.

## General Privacy Policy

It is our policy to preserve the privacy of personal records and to protect confidential or privileged information. Such information will be disclosed publicly only as required by the Public Information Act or as necessary or permissible to carry out official duties. Under State law, these policies do not apply to information gathered for certain specified purposes, such as the investigation of a possible violation of the law. If you have any questions about these privacy policies, please e-mail support.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Changes to our websites may necessitate changes to our privacy statement. Notification will be posted on the WWW.MARYLAND.GOV website homepage in the Privacy Notice link. The information contained in this privacy statement applies only to WWW.MARYLAND.GOV and other State agency websites that have been authorized to link to this policy, and not to any linked sites or all websites maintained by Maryland State agencies. You should review the individual privacy statements at any linked site that you visit.

## Site Security

To ensure that Maryland.gov is secure and remains available to all users, the Maryland Department of Information Technology employs commercial software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under State and Federal laws that protect fraud and abuse of computer systems. ​
